Guide to the David Conner Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
David Conner papers
1845-1846
WA MSS S-342
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
0.5
(1 box)
The collection contains letters to and from David Conner, third party correspondence, and proclamations of the Mexican government, concerning the war between Mexico and the United States, particularly about the Yucatan.
Conner, David, 1792-1856
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Please consult the appropriate curator.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
The collection contains letters to and from David Conner, third party correspondence, and proclamations of the Mexican government, concerning the war between Mexico and the United States, particulary about the Yucatan.
Mexican War, 1846-1848 -- Naval operations; Public officers -- United States; Conner, David, 1792-1856; Dimond, Francis M.; Hunt, William E(William Egar); McFaul, Eneas; Shannon, Wilson, 1802-1877; Slidell, John, 1793-1871; Porpoise (Brig); Yucatán (Mexico: State). Congreso
- Box and folder list, 1845 May 21, 22
  - Conner, David. AL and copy of LS to Wilson Shannon. U.S.S. Potomac, off Vera Cruz., 1845 May 21, 22 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Scope and Contents
    Concerning transportation to the U.S. for Shannon, U.S. minister to Mexico.
  - Copy (translated) of a notice accompanying the Pronunciamento of the Congress at Merida, taken from a Yucatanian Newspaper., [1846] (Box 1, Folder 2)
    "Received Sept. 7".
  - Hunt, William E. ALS to David Conner. Brig Porpoise, off Anton Lizardo., 1846 Sep 7 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Report of his cruise to Laguna and back.
  - McFaul, Eneas.
    - Copy of LS to Wm. E. Hunt. Laguna, Mexico., 1846 Aug 26 (Box 1, Folder 4)
      Concerns affairs in Yucatan.
    - LS to David Conner. Laguna, Mex., 1846 Sep 3 (Box 1, Folder 5)
      Concerned with the situation in Yucatan.
  - Shannon, Wilson.
    - ALS to F. M. Dimond. Jalapa, Mex., 1845 May 18 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - 2 ALS to David Conner. Jalapa, Mex., 1845 May 18, 23 (Box 1, Folder 7)
      Concerns arrangements for passage to New Orleans.
  - Slidell, John. 12 ALS to David Conner. New Orleans, Jalapa and Vera Cruz., 1845-46 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    Mainly concerned with the legation of the U.S.A. in Mexico.
  - Yucatan, Congreso. Declaration of Yucatan., [1846] (Box 1, Folder 9)
    Translated by Charles B. Young. Announces that Yucatan will adhere to the plan of Guadalajara and recognize Santa Anna as President.